Guide to the Czesław Miłosz Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1946-2000; Series I; 32.11; (78 boxes)
  - General Correspondence
    - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 157)
    - Bell, Daniel, 1953-1990 (Box 8, Folder 158)
    - Bellarmine College, 1983-1988 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - Bellow, Saul, 1977-1988 (Box 8, Folder 160)
    - Benzion, Hannah, 1958-1965 (Box 8, Folder 161-162)
    - Bereś, Stanisław, 1978-1990 (Box 8, Folder 163)
    - Berghash, Rachel, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 164)
    - Bertelsmann Publishing, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Białoszewski, Miron, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - Błoński, Jan, 1958-1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 167-169)
      See also: Jagiellonian University
    - Bobowicz, Zofia, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 170)
    - Bocheński, Ignacy Maria, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 171)
    - Bochwic, Bolesław, 1967-1993, undated (Box 9, Folder 172-173)
    - Borejsza, Jerzy, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - Borowik, Aniela, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 175)
      To Janina Miłosz.
    - Borwicz, Michał, 1955-1958 (Box 9, Folder 176)
    - Borysewicz, Krystyna, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 177)
    - Bourgeois, Robert, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 178)
    - Boxberg, Katharina von, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - Brandeis University, 1980-1988 (Box 9, Folder 180)
    - Brandys, Kazimierz, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 181)
    - Brezhnev, Leonid, outgoing (copy), 1981 (Box 9, Folder 182)
    - Briarwood Writer's Alliance, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 183)
    - Britanishskii, Vladimir, 1989-1992 (Box 9, Folder 184)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1956-1992 (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Brkić, Vesna, 1984-1990 (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - Brodsky, David, 1968-1977 (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, incoming and outgoing, 1972-1988 (Box 10, Folder 188)
      Microfilm available.
    - Brombergs Bokförlag, 1979-1990 (Box 10, Folder 189-190)
    - Broncel, Zdzisław, 1955-1959 (Box 10, Folder 191)
    - Broniewska, Wanda, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 192)
    - Brumberg, Abraham, incoming and outgoing, 1956-1981 (Box 10, Folder 193)
    - Bryll, Ernest, 1970-1977 (Box 10, Folder 194)
    - Brzeski, Andrzej and Nancy, 1962-1990, undated (Box 10, Folder 195)
    - Bureau d'Informations Polonaises (Paris), outgoing, 1947 or 1948 (Box 10, Folder 196)
    - Burian, Vaclav, 1987-1999 (Box 10, Folder 197)
    - Busza, Andrzej, 1967-1970 (Box 10, Folder 198)
    - Buttinger, Joe & Muriel, 1959-1965 (Box 10, Folder 199)
    - Buxell, Tomira W., 1970-1990 (Box 10, Folder 200)
    - Byrski, Tadeusz and family, 1948-1988 (Box 10, Folder 201-203)
    - "Ca-Co" general (Box 11, Folder 204-212)
    - "Cr-Cz" general (Box 12, Folder 213-214)
    - Camus, Albert, 1952-1957, undated (Box 12, Folder 215)
    - Carl Hanser Verlag, 1964-1995 (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - Carpenter, John R. and Bogdana, 1974-1991 (Box 12, Folder 217)
      Includes a letter to Renata Gorczyńska.
    - Cassou, Jean, 1954-1980 (Box 12, Folder 218)
    - Cataluccio, Francesco M., 1988-1992 (Box 12, Folder 219)
    - Centralne Archiwum Polonii, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 220)
    - Centre Européen de la Culture, 1953-1981 (Box 12, Folder 221-222)
    - Chabrowski, Wacław, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 223)
    - Charbonnier, G. Alexandra, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 224)
    - Chciuk, Andrzej, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 225)
    - Chiaromonte, Nicola and Miriam, 1956-1988 (Box 12, Folder 226)
    - Chojecki, Mirosław, 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 227)
    - Choynowski, Mieczysław, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 228)
    - Chrabolowski, Andrzej, 1989-1993, undated (Box 12, Folder 229)
    - City Arts & Lectures, 1990-1996 (Box 12, Folder 230)
    - Claremont McKenna College, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 231)
      See also: Faggen, Robert
    - Columbia University, 1988-1996 (Box 12, Folder 232)
    - Congrès pour la Liberté de la Culture, 1951-1959 (Box 12, Folder 233)
      See also: Jeleński, Konstanty
    - Conrad, Joseph (copy of a 1924 letter to unidentified recipient, not Czesław Miłosz), undated (Box 12, Folder 234)
    - Contemporary Authors, 1968-1993 (Box 12, Folder 235)
    - Continuum Books, 1973-1993 (Box 12, Folder 236)
    - Cosanti Foundation, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 237)
    - Cox, Harvey, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 238)
    - Cuddihy, Michael
      See: Ironwood Press
    - Curtis Brown, Ltd., 1960-1961 (Box 13, Folder 239)
    - Czapski, Józef and Maria, 1951-1987 (Box 13, Folder 240-245)
    - Czaykowski, Bogdan, 1958-1976 (Box 13, Folder 246)
    - Czerniawski, Adam, 1961-1963 (Box 13, Folder 247)
    - Czycz, Stanisław, undated (Box 13, Folder 248)
    - Czytelnik (firm), 1974-1998 (Box 13, Folder 249)
      See also: Kłoczowski, Piotr
    - Czyżewski, Krzysztof, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 250)
    - "D" general (Box 14, Folder 251-258)
    - Dainauskas, Jonas, incoming and outgoing, 1950s-1967 (Box 15, Folder 259)
    - Danilewicz Zielińska, Maria, 1981-1985 (Box 15, Folder 260)
    - Darowski, Jan, 1970-1973 (Box 15, Folder 261)
    - Dedecius, Karl, 1958-1978, undated (Box 15, Folder 262)
      See also: Deutsches Polen Institut
    - Deutsches Polen Institut, 1980-1993 (Box 15, Folder 263)
    - Dłuska, Elżbieta, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 264)
    - Dłuski, Stanisław, 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 265)
    - Dłuski, Tadeusz, 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 266)
    - Dobak, Anna, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 267)
    - Doboszyński, Leon, 1988-1990 (Box 15, Folder 268)
    - Doubleday & Company, 1964-1990 (Box 15, Folder 269)
    - Dougherty, Kate, 1983-1990 (Box 15, Folder 270)
    - Drabik, Grażyna, 1979-1982 (Box 15, Folder 271-272)
    - Duhamel, Georges, 1954-1956 (Box 15, Folder 273)
    - Dziewicka, M., 1987-1991 (Box 15, Folder 274)
    - "E" general (Box 15, Folder 275-277)
    - Ecco Press, 1977-1996 (Box 16, Folder 278)
    - Editions du Dialogue, 1978-1994 (Box 16, Folder 279)
    - Editions L'Age d'Homme, 1976-1980 (Box 16, Folder 280)
    - Editions Noir sur Blanc, 1987-1995 (Box 16, Folder 281)
    - Editorial Universitaria (San Juan, P.R.), 1953-1958 (Box 16, Folder 282)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1951-1953 (Box 16, Folder 283)
    - Elektorowicz, Leszek, 1957-1967 (Box 16, Folder 284)
    - Elie Wiesel Foundation for Humanity, 1987-1988 (Box 16, Folder 285)
    - Eliot, T.S., 1945-1951 (Box 16, Folder 286)
    - Emory University, 1982-1993 (Box 16, Folder 287)
    - Encounter, 1954-1962 (Box 16, Folder 288)
    - Engle, Paul, 1966-1983 (Box 16, Folder 289)
    - Eurographica, 1985-1993 (Box 16, Folder 290)
    - "Fa-Fo" general (Box 16, Folder 291-295)
    - "Fr-Fu" general (Box 17, Folder 296-297)
    - Faggen, Robert, 1990-1995 (Box 17, Folder 298)
    - Fałtynowicz, Zbigniew, 1988-1991 (Box 17, Folder 299)
    - Farrar, Strauss & Giroux, 1978-1998 (Box 17, Folder 300-301)
    - Fiszman, Samuel and Alicja, 1973-1997, undated (Box 17, Folder 302)
    - Fiut, Aleksander, 1976-1995, undated (Box 17, Folder 303-304)
    - Fnac (Paris), 1983 (Box 17, Folder 305)
    - Folejewski, Zbigniew, 1960-1992 (Box 17, Folder 306)
    - Folger Shakespeare Library, 1993-1994 (Box 17, Folder 307)
    - Fondation pour une Entraide Intellectuelle Européenne, 1979-1990 (Box 17, Folder 308)
    - Fonds d'Aide Aux Lettres Polonaises Indépendantes, 1982-1997 (Box 18, Folder 309)
    - Ford Foundation, 1980-1984 (Box 18, Folder 310)
    - Forum, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 311)
    - Frajlich-Zając, Anna, 1988-1996 (Box 18, Folder 312)
      See also: Columbia University
    - Freedman, John, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 313)
    - Frybes, Stanisław, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 314)
    - Fuhrman, Krystyna, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 315)
    - "Ga-Go" general (Box 18, Folder 316-322)
    - "Gr-Gy" general (Box 19, Folder 323-326)
    - Gach, Gary, 1990-1997, undated (Box 19, Folder 327)
    - Gallimard (firm), 1953-1980 (Box 19, Folder 328)
      See also: Camus, Albert
    - Garcelon, Ewa, 1991-1992 (Box 19, Folder 329)
    - Gerlach, Roman T., 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 330)
    - Giedroyc, Jerzy, incoming and outgoing, 1952-1963 (Box 19, Folder 331-333)
    - Giedroyc, Jerzy, incoming and outgoing, 1964-1998 (Box 20, Folder 334-341)
      Includes third-party correspondence from others to Giedroyc.
    - Giedroyc, Jerzy, third party, 1958-1991 (Box 20, Folder 342)
    - Giertych, Jędrzej, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 343)
    - Gilbert, Erin, 1992-1995 (Box 21, Folder 344)
    - Ginsberg, Allen, 1986-1993 (Box 21, Folder 345)
    - Glickstein, Gloria, 1987-1990 (Box 21, Folder 346)
    - Gocel, Ludwik, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 347)
    - Gołębiowska, Wanda, 1981-2001 (Box 21, Folder 348)
    - Gombrowicz, Rita, 1967-1992 (Box 21, Folder 349)
    - Gombrowicz, Witold, 1954-1969 (Box 21, Folder 350)
    - Gömöri, George, 1962-1993 (Box 21, Folder 351)
    - Goodman, Mac and Sheba, 1951-1977 (Box 21, Folder 352)
    - Gorczyńska, Renata, 1979-1998 (Box 21, Folder 353)
    - Górska-Damięcka, Irena, 1981-1997, undated (Box 21, Folder 354-355)
    - Goszczyńska, Henryka, 1946-1980 (Box 21, Folder 356)
    - Goślicki, Jan, 1968-1969 (Box 21, Folder 357-358)
    - Goślicki, Jan, 1970-1989, undated (Box 22, Folder 359-368)
    - Grabowski, Zbigniew, 1956-1958 (Box 23, Folder 369)
    - Grade, Inna Hecker, 1987-1994 (Box 23, Folder 370)
    - Grassi, Carolyn Cook, 1981-1988 (Box 23, Folder 371)
    - Gray, Rockwell, 1986-1990 (Box 23, Folder 372)
    - Grover, Owen
      See: Gilbert, Erin
    - Greppin, John A. C., 1985-1995 (Box 23, Folder 373)
    - Grosjean, Ok-Koo, 1981-1998 (Box 23, Folder 374)
    - Gross, Feliks, 1965-1982 (Box 23, Folder 375)
    - Gross, Natan, incoming and outgoing, 1982-1994 (Box 23, Folder 376)
    - Gruber, Katarzyna, 1979-1988 (Box 23, Folder 377)
    - Grygiel, Stanisław, 1980-1982 (Box 23, Folder 378)
    - Grynberg, Henryk, 1968-1996 (Box 23, Folder 379)
    - Guilde du Livre
      See: Centre Europeen de la Culture
    - Guillén, Claudio, 1980-1993 (Box 23, Folder 380)
    - Guillén, Jorge, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 381)
    - Guze, Zygmunt, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 382)
    - "H.-Har" general (Box 23, Folder 383-384)
    - "Hat-Hy" general (Box 24, Folder 385-391)
    - Hainard, Robert, 1955-1957 (Box 24, Folder 392)
    - Halpern, Daniel, 1982-1993 (Box 24, Folder 393)
      See also: Ecco Press
    - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1961-1991 (Box 24, Folder 394)
    - Hartwig, Julia
      See: Międzyrzecki, Artur
    - Harvard University, 1980-1991 (Box 24, Folder 395)
    - Hass, Robert, 1988 (Box 24, Folder 396)
      Other correspondence with Robert Hass is filed with translations of Miłosz's poetry in Series II.
    - Havel, Vaclav, incoming and outgoing, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 397)
    - Heaney, Seamus, 1987-1999 (Box 24, Folder 398)
    - Herbert, Zbigniew, 1958-1990 (Box 25, Folder 399-401)
    - Herling-Grudziński, Gustaw, 1960-1988 (Box 25, Folder 402)
    - Hersch, Jeanne, 1952-1997, undated (Box 25, Folder 403-406)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Formerly restricted until 2010.
    - Hersey, John, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 407)
    - Hertz, Aleksander, 1969-1979 (Box 26, Folder 408)
    - Hertz, Paweł, 1958-1998 (Box 26, Folder 409)
    - Hertz, Zygmunt and Zofia, 1952-1966 (Box 26, Folder 410-418)
    - Hertz, Zygmunt and Zofia, 1967-1977 (Box 27, Folder 419-429)
    - Hertz, Zygmunt and Zofia, 1978-1998, undated (Box 28, Folder 430-432)
    - Hłasko, Marek, outgoing, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 433)
    - Horodyński, Dominik, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 434)
    - Hordyński, Jerzy, 1968-1978 (Box 28, Folder 435)
    - Howard, John, outgoing, undated (Box 28, Folder 436)
    - Howe, Irving, 1957-1959 (Box 28, Folder 437)
    - Huerta, Alberto, 1982-1996 (Box 28, Folder 438)
    - Humphrey, Lisa, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 439)
    - Hunt, John C., incoming and outgoing, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 440)
    - Huntington Hartford Foundation, incoming and outgoing, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 441)
    - "I" general (Box 28, Folder 442-444)
    - Illg, Jerzy, 1987-1993, undated (Box 29, Folder 445)
    - Indiana University, 1960-1988 (Box 29, Folder 446)
    - Institut International. Jacques Maritan., 1980-1993 (Box 29, Folder 447)
    - Institut Littéraire, 1970-1999, undated (Box 29, Folder 448-449)
      See also: Giedroyc, Jerzy, Herling-Grudziński, Gustaw, Hertz, Zygmunt and Zofia, and Kultura.
    - Iribarne, Louis, 1968-1973 (Box 29, Folder 450)
    - Ironwood Press, 1980-1988 (Box 29, Folder 451)
    - Istner, Filip, 1970-1990 (Box 29, Folder 452)
    - Ivask, Ivar and Astrid, 1976-1993 (Box 29, Folder 453)
    - Iwaniuk, Wacław, 1962 (Box 29, Folder 454)
    - Iwańska, Alicja, 1961-1995 (Box 29, Folder 455)
    - Iwaszkiewicz, Jarosław, 1959-1979 (Box 29, Folder 456)
    - Iwaszkiewicz, Maria, 1961-1998 (Box 29, Folder 457)
    - "Jab-Jano" general (Box 29, Folder 458-459)
    - "Janz-Ju" general (Box 30, Folder 460-463)
    - Jagiellonian University, 1980-1989 (Box 30, Folder 464)
      See also: Uniwersytet Jagielloński.
    - Jameson, Margaret Storm, incoming, outgoing and third-party, 1946-1980 (Box 30, Folder 465-471)
    - Janta-Polczyński, Aleksander, 1948-1967 (Box 30, Folder 472)
    - Jarzębski, Jerzy, 1981-1997 (Box 30, Folder 473)
    - Jaspers, Karl, 1953-1956 (Box 30, Folder 474)
    - Jastrun, Mieczysław, 1957-1964 (Box 30, Folder 475)
    - Jeleński, Konstanty, incoming, 1953-1982 (Box 31, Folder 476-484)
      Correspondence between Jeleński and Miłosz is discussed in letters from Kłoczowski, Piotr.
    - Jeleński, Konstanty, incoming, 1983-1987 (Box 32, Folder 485-486)
    - Jeleński, Konstanty, outgoing, 1962-1987, undated (Box 32, Folder 487-490)
    - Jenne, Beniamin Józef, 1960-1966 (Box 32, Folder 491)
    - Jeżewski, Krzysztof, 1984-1989 (Box 32, Folder 492)
    - John Paul II, Pope, 1981 (Box 32, Folder 493)
    - John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation, 1981-1989 (Box 32, Folder 494)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1976-1993 (Box 32, Folder 495)
    - Jones, Jack, 1959 (Box 32, Folder 496)
    - [Josselson, Michael?], outgoing, undated (Box 32, Folder 497)
    - Jurewicz, Aleksander, 1986-1997 (Box 32, Folder 498)
    - Jurewicz-Hajdusz, Janina, 1986-1989 (Box 32, Folder 499)
    - "Ka-Kol" general (Box 33, Folder 500-506)
    - "Kom-Kru" general (Box 34, Folder 507-513)
    - "Kry-Ky" general (Box 35, Folder 514-516)
    - Kalinowska, Fryderyka, 1968-1972 (Box 35, Folder 517)
    - Kang, Ok-koo
      See: Grosjean, Ok-koo
    - Kaniewicz, Jerzy, 1965-1967 (Box 35, Folder 518)
    - Karpiński, Wojciech, 1965-2000 (Box 35, Folder 519)
    - Karpowicz, Tymoteusz, 1958-1991 (Box 35, Folder 520)
    - Katolicki Uniwersytet Lubelski, 1980-1987 (Box 35, Folder 521)
    - Kekśtas, J., 1953-1954 (Box 35, Folder 522)
    - Kęsik, Andrzej, 1987-1990 (Box 35, Folder 523)
    - Kierlanczyk, Aurelia, 1988-1991 (Box 35, Folder 524)
    - Kijowski, Andrzej, 1971-1981 (Box 35, Folder 525)
    - King, Janna, 1995-1996 (Box 35, Folder 526)
    - Kisielewski, Stefan, 1955-1988 (Box 35, Folder 527)
    - Kissinger, Henry A., incoming and outgoing, 1955-1975 (Box 36, Folder 528)
    - Kjellberg, Ann, 1987-1996 (Box 36, Folder 529)
    - Klahs, Cyprian Adam, 1992-1998 (Box 36, Folder 530)
    - Kłoczowski, Jerzy, 1980-1992 (Box 36, Folder 531)
    - Kłoczowski, Piotr, 1980-1996 (Box 36, Folder 532)
    - Kłus, Mark, 1977-1997 (Box 36, Folder 533)
    - Kolankowska, Kazimiera, 1994-1998 (Box 36, Folder 534)
    - Kołyszko, Ryszard
      See: Siedlar, Teresa
    - Kołakowski, Leszek, 1970-1992 (Box 36, Folder 535)
    - Kontynenty (London), incoming and outgoing, 1955-1964 (Box 36, Folder 536)
    - Konwicki, Tadeusz, 1976-1981 (Box 36, Folder 537)
    - Korabiewicz, Wacław, 1953-1985, undated (Box 36, Folder 538)
    - Koralnik, Eva
      See: Ruth Liepman
    - Kościałkowska, Janina, 1989-1994 (Box 36, Folder 539)
    - Kosciuszko Foundation, 1974-1996 (Box 36, Folder 540)
    - Kott, Jan, 1965-1978 (Box 36, Folder 541)
    - Kowalczykowa, Alina, 1989-1998, undated (Box 36, Folder 542-543)
      Includes a printout of transcripts of letters from Miłosz to Wat for Korespondencja ( Pisma Zebrane, Aleksander Wat)
    - Kownacki, Stanisław, 1957-1991 (Box 37, Folder 544)
    - KQED, 1968-1990 (Box 37, Folder 545)
    - Kraus, Wacława H., 1968 (Box 37, Folder 546)
    - Kridl, Manfred, 1955 (Box 37, Folder 547)
    - Krońska, Irena, 1948-1973 (Box 37, Folder 548-550)
    - Krońska-Beby, Ludwika (Louise), 1968-1990, undated (Box 37, Folder 551)
    - Kruszewski, Zygmunt, 1957-1971 (Box 37, Folder 552)
    - Kultura, 1958-1982 (Box 37, Folder 553)
    - Kundera, Milan, 1988 (Box 37, Folder 554)
    - Kunicki, Jan, 1987-1992 (Box 37, Folder 555)
    - Kuryluk, Karol (transcripts), 1949 (Box 37, Folder 556)
    - "La" general (Box 37, Folder 557-559)
    - "Le-Ly" general (Box 38, Folder 560-566)
    - Landsbergis, Algirdas, 1964-1989, undated (Box 38, Folder 567)
    - Langer, Rulka, incoming and outgoing, 1955-1958 (Box 38, Folder 568)
    - Leach, Catherine, 1964-1982 (Box 38, Folder 569)
    - Lebenstein, Jan, 1965-1990, undated (Box 38, Folder 570)
    - Lednicki, Wacław, 1956-1960 (Box 39, Folder 571)
    - Levertov, Denise, 1991-1997 (Box 39, Folder 572)
    - Levine, Madeline, 1989-1998 (Box 39, Folder 573)
    - Lewandowski, Wacław, 1989-1992 (Box 39, Folder 574)
    - Libraire Arthème Fayard, 1986-1989 (Box 39, Folder 575)
    - Library of Congress, 1991-1992 (Box 39, Folder 576)
    - Liepman AG, 1973-1989 (Box 39, Folder 577)
    - Lieven, Anatol, 1991-1995 (Box 39, Folder 578)
    - Lindsfarne Association, 1980-1991 (Box 39, Folder 579)
    - Lipski, Leo, 1957-1969 (Box 39, Folder 580)
    - Lipski, Władysław, Elżbieta and Nina, 1961-1976 (Box 39, Folder 581-582)
    - Lis, Grzegorz, 1990-1997 (Box 39, Folder 583)
    - Lisowski, Jerzy
      See: Twórczość
    - Lizakowski, Adam, 1986-1998 (Box 39, Folder 584)
    - Loepfe, Alfred, 1952-1974 (Box 39, Folder 585)
    - Lordly & Dame, 1985-1990 (Box 39, Folder 586)
      Some Lordly & Dame correspondence related to Miłosz's appearances is filed under the name of the institution visited.
    - Lourie, Richard, 1973-1996 (Box 39, Folder 587)
    - Łabędź, Leopold, 1960-1980 (Box 39, Folder 588)
    - "Ma-Mc" general (Box 40, Folder 589-595)
    - "Me-My" general (Box 41, Folder 596-602)
    - Machej, Zbigniew, 1988-1993 (Box 42, Folder 603)
    - Mackiewicz, Józef, 1954-1970 (Box 42, Folder 604)
    - MacMillan Publishing Company, 1965-1981 (Box 42, Folder 605)
    - Maisel, B., 1963-1964 (Box 42, Folder 606)
    - Maj, Bronisław, 1986-1990 (Box 42, Folder 607)
    - Malinowska, Halina, 1985-1993 (Box 42, Folder 608)
    - Mandel, Artur, 1967-1973 (Box 42, Folder 609)
    - Manly, Morse, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 610)
    - Marchesani, Pietro, 1981-1995 (Box 42, Folder 611)
    - Maritain, Jacques, incoming and outgoing, 1947-1952 (Box 42, Folder 612)
    - Martin, Secker & Warburg, 1952-1981 (Box 42, Folder 613)
    - Matuszewski, Ryszard, incoming and outgoing, 1972-1996 (Box 42, Folder 614)
    - Maurer, Jadwiga, 1968-1997 (Box 42, Folder 615)
    - Mayewski, Paweł, incoming and outgoing, 1957-1965, 1994 (Box 42, Folder 616)
      Includes transcripts and copies made in 1994.
    - Mencwel, Andrzej, 1985-1996 (Box 42, Folder 617)
    - Merrill, Charles E., Jr., 1959-1997 (Box 42, Folder 618)
    - Merton, Thomas, 1959-1968 (Box 42, Folder 619)
      The file includes only some of the correspondence printed in Striving towards being: the letters of Thomas Merton and Czeslaw Milosz. Miłosz donated the remainder to Bellarmine College.
    - Merwin, W.S., 1964-1995 (Box 42, Folder 620)
    - Michajłów, Adam, 1988-1989 (Box 43, Folder 621)
    - Michalska, Ela, 1991, undated (Box 43, Folder 622)
    - Michnik, Adam, 1987, 1996 (Box 43, Folder 623)
    - Micińska, Aniela
      See: Ulatowski, Jan
    - Micińska, Anna and Włodzimierz Zagórski, 1967-1997, undated (Box 43, Folder 624)
      Includes copies and transcripts of letters from Miłosz to Halina and Bolesław Micinski (1939-1944).
    - Międzyrzecki, Artur and Julia Hartwig, 1971-1974 (Box 43, Folder 625-629)
    - Międzyrzecki, Artur and Julia Hartwig, 1975-1988 (Box 44, Folder 630-631)
    - Miller, Henry, 1948-1959 (Box 44, Folder 632)
    - Miłosz, Aleksander, 1956-1959 (Box 44, Folder 633)
    - Miłosz, Andrzej and Grażyna, 1948-2000 (Box 44, Folder 634-638)
    - Miłosz, Anthony Oscar, 1991-1996 (Box 44, Folder 639)
    - Miłosz, Janina, 1950-1966 (Box 44, Folder 640-642)
    - Miłosz, Joanna, 1970-1994 (Box 45, Folder 643)
    - Miłosz, John Peter, 1975-1997 (Box 45, Folder 644)
    - Miłosz, Olga, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 645)
    - Mishkenot Sha'ananim, 1989-1998 (Box 45, Folder 646)
    - Misiewicz, Bogusław, 1990-1995 (Box 45, Folder 647)
    - Morawiec, Elżbieta, 1978-1993 (Box 45, Folder 648)
    - Możejko, Edward, 1987-1988 (Box 45, Folder 649)
    - Mrożek, Sławomir, 1963-1987 (Box 45, Folder 650)
    - Muszer, Dariusz, 1984-1991 (Box 45, Folder 651)
    - Muzeum Literatury im. Adama Mickiewicza, 1968-1995 (Box 45, Folder 652)
    - Mycielski, Zygmunt, incoming and outgoing, 1948-1987 (Box 45, Folder 653)
    - Myszkowski, Krzysztof, 1993-1999 (Box 45, Folder 654)
    - "N" general (Box 46, Folder 655-660)
    - Naef, Hélène, 1960-1966 (Box 46, Folder 661)
    - Nagy, Andras, 1988-1989 (Box 46, Folder 662)
    - Najder, Zdzisław, 1962-1973 (Box 46, Folder 663)
    - Narzymska, Zofia, 1981-1994, undated (Box 46, Folder 664)
    - Nathan, Leonard, 1980-1994 (Box 46, Folder 665)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1985-1990, undated (Box 46, Folder 666)
    - Neruda, Pablo, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 667)
    - New-Land Foundation, Inc., 1959-1961 (Box 47, Folder 668)
    - New Republic, 1983-1993, undated (Box 47, Folder 669)
    - New York Review of Books, 1977-1998 (Box 47, Folder 670)
    - New York Times, 1965-1990 (Box 47, Folder 671)
    - New Yorker, 1953-1998 (Box 47, Folder 672)
      See also: Whitney Museum of American Art
    - Niementowska, Janina, 1960-1975 (Box 47, Folder 673)
    - Niemiec, Maciej, 1989-1992 (Box 47, Folder 674)
    - Nobelstiftelsen, 1990-1991 (Box 47, Folder 675)
    - Norske Nobelinstitute, 1982-1989 (Box 47, Folder 676)
    - Northwestern University Press, 1988-1991 (Box 47, Folder 677)
    - Novak, Michael, outgoing, undated (Box 47, Folder 678)
    - Nowosad, Tadeusz, 1986-1991 (Box 47, Folder 679)
    - Nycz, Ryszard, 1991-1994 (Box 47, Folder 680)
    - "O" general (Box 47, Folder 681-683)
    - Odrodzenie, outgoing (letter to the editors), 1948? (Box 47, Folder 684)
    - Okulicz, Kazimierz, 1967-1979 (Box 47, Folder 685)
    - Opal, Chester H., 1993-1994 (Box 47, Folder 686)
    - Oslobodenje, outgoing (letter to the editors), 1993 (Box 47, Folder 687)
    - "Pa-Pl" general (Box 48, Folder 688-695)
    - "Po-Py" general (Box 49, Folder 696-702)
    - Pantheon Books, 1960-1989 (Box 49, Folder 703)
    - Państwowy Instytut Wydawniczy, 1957-1995 (Box 49, Folder 704)
    - Papini, Roberto
      See: Institut International Jacques Maritain
    - Paris Review, 1985-1989 (Box 49, Folder 705)
    - [Parnicki, Teodor?], 1954 (Box 50, Folder 706)
    - Partisan Review, 1962-1995 (Box 50, Folder 707)
    - Pawlikowska, Maria, 1958-1965 (Box 50, Folder 708)
    - Paz, Octavio, 1971 (Box 50, Folder 709)
    - Peabody, Mary, 1990-1996 (Box 50, Folder 710)
    - Peel, Jane and Suzi, 1952-1982 (Box 50, Folder 711)
      See also: Postwar Correspondence (under Zielonko, Jane).
    - PEN, 1956-1992s (Box 50, Folder 712-713)
    - Penguin Books, 1965-1988 (Box 50, Folder 714)
      See also: Alvarez, Alfred
    - Pieczyńska, Czesława, 1988-1990 (Box 50, Folder 715)
    - Piel, François, 1990 (Box 50, Folder 716)
    - Pieraccini, Roland
      See: Eurographica
    - Poetry Center, 1968-1987 (Box 50, Folder 717)
    - Poetry Society (London), 1988-1996 (Box 50, Folder 718)
    - Poetry Society of America, 1980-1994 (Box 50, Folder 719)
    - Polanyi, Michael, 1952-1953 (Box 50, Folder 720)